Laura Alabau

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

I have experience working as a frontend developer and as a graphic designer, with a wide range of technical skills such as JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, React, and more. My knowledge in UI/UX design sets me apart in understanding user behavior and creating intuitive designs.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer / Prima

Sep, 2024 - Current / Remote

- React, Typescript, Elm, and SCSS to develop and maintain frontend applications, leveraging a shared design system and microfrontend architecture (Module Federation).
- Occasional backend contributions with Elixir and GraphQL. Ensured 100% test coverage with Vitest and maintained high code quality using Git and GitHub.

Frontend Developer / Jobandtalent

Dec, 2021 - May, 2024 / Remote

- Typescript, React, Tailwind, Zod, Jest, and more to develop and maintain web interfaces, ensuring optimal user experience and functionality.
- Implement best practices for front-end development, including version control with Git, to ensure high code quality and maintainability.

Web & UI Designer / Entain

Apr, 2019 - Aug, 2021 / Barcelona and remote

- Design visually captivating web interfaces, incorporating UX and UI principles to enhance user engagement and interaction.
- Collaborate with development teams to ensure a seamless integration of designs into functional and responsive web applications.

UI/UX Designer & HMI Concept / Rucker Lypsa for SEAT

Oct, 2017 - Apr, 2019 / Martorell

- Collaborate with development teams to integrate HMI concepts into functional and visually appealing automotive interfaces.
- Manage the creative process from concept to completion, ensuring all projects were delivered on time.

Web and Graphic designer / Dinàmic Comunicació

Jan, 2016 - Jul, 2017 / Barcelona

- Create art assets for multiple platforms and devices, including web, mobile, and print.
- Design and develop a custom CMS for a web application that allowed easy content management and updates.

Graphic designer / Offerum & Groupalia

Nov, 2014 - Dec, 2015 / Barcelona

- Use a variety of software tools to create high-quality visuals, including Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, and Illustrator.
- Optimize digital images for web and mobile platforms, resulting in faster page loading times.

EDUCATION

2021 | Bootcamp

Fullstack Web Development

IRONHACK

2016-2017 | Course

HTML & CSS

UOC

2011-2012 | Degree

Industrial Design and Product Development

UDC

2006-2010 | Technical Engineering

Industrial Design

UDC

LANGUAGES

Spanish

English

Galician

Catalan

SKILLS

HTML + CSS

JavaScript + TypeScript

React

Jest

Zod Git

MongoDB

NodeJS

Express

SOCIAL

laura-alabau.com

in laura-alabau-rodriguez

!auraAlabau